<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quansight Labs (Posts by Gonzalo Peña-Castellanos)</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://labs.quansight.org/authors/gonzalo-pena-castellanos.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:info@quansight.com"&gt;Quansight Labs Team&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 14:35:01 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>TDK-Micronas partners with Quansight to sponsor Spyder</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2019/06/tdk-partners-with-quansight-labs/</link><dc:creator>Gonzalo Peña-Castellanos</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;TDK-Micronas is sponsoring Spyder development efforts through Quansight Labs.
This will enable the development of some features that have been requested by
our users, as well as new features that will help TDK develop custom Spyder
plugins in order to complement their Automatic Test Equipment (ATE’s) in the
development of their Application Specific Integrated Circuits (ASIC’s).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point it may be useful to clarify the relationship the role of
Quansight Labs in Spyder's development and the relationship with TDK. To quote
Ralf Gommers (director of Quansight Labs):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"We're an R&amp;amp;D lab for open source development of core technologies around data
science and scientific computing in Python. And focused on growing communities
around those technologies. That's how I see it for Spyder as well: Quansight
Labs enables developers to be employed to work on Spyder, and helps with
connecting them to developers of other projects in similar situations. Labs
should be an enabler to let the Spyder project, its community and individual
developers grow. And Labs provides mechanisms to attract and coordinate
funding. Of course the project is still independent. If there are other
funding sources, e.g. donations from individuals to Spyder via OpenCollective,
all the better."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Multiple Projects aka Workspaces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In its current state Spyder can only handle one active project at a time.
Although in the past we had basic support for workspaces, it was never a fully
functional feature, so to ease development and simplify the user experience,
we decided to remove it in the 3.x series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2019/06/tdk-partners-with-quansight-labs/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Labs</category><category>Spyder</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2019/06/tdk-partners-with-quansight-labs/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 05:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spyder 4.0 takes a big step closer with the release of Beta 2!</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2019/05/spyder-4-beta2-release/</link><dc:creator>Gonzalo Peña-Castellanos</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has been almost two months since I joined Quansight in April, to start 
working on Spyder maintenance and 
development. So far, it has been a very exciting and rewarding journey under 
the guidance of long time Spyder maintainer
&lt;a href="https://github.com/ccordoba12"&gt;Carlos Córdoba&lt;/a&gt;.
This is the first of a series of blog posts we will be writing to showcase 
updates on the development of Spyder, new planned features and news on the 
road to Spyder 4.0 and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First off, I would like to give a warm welcome to
&lt;a href="https://github.com/andfoy"&gt;Edgar Margffoy&lt;/a&gt;,
who recently joined Quansight and will be working with the Spyder team to
take its development even further. Edgar has been a core Spyder developer 
for more than two years now, and we are very excited to have his (almost)
full-time commitment to the project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Spyder 4.0 Beta 2 released!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since August 2018, when the first beta of the 4.x series was released, the
Spyder development team has been working hard on our next release.
Over the past year, we've implemented the long awaited full-interface dark theme;
overhauled our entire code completion and linting architecture to use the
&lt;a href="https://microsoft.github.io/language-server-protocol/"&gt;Language Server Protocol&lt;/a&gt;,
opening the door to supporting many other languages in the future;
added a new Plots pane to view and manage the figures generated by your code;
and numerous other feature enhancements, bug fixes and internal improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dark theme&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A full-interface dark theme has been a
&lt;a href="https://github.com/spyder-ide/spyder/issues/2350"&gt;long awaited feature&lt;/a&gt;,
and is enabled by default in Spyder 4. You can still select the
light theme under  &lt;code&gt;Preferences &amp;gt; Appearance&lt;/code&gt; by either choosing a light-background
syntax-highlighting scheme, or changing &lt;code&gt;Interface theme&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Light&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Screenshot of the Spyder main window with default panes, with the dark theme applied across the entire interface" src="https://labs.quansight.org/images/spyder-qdarkstyle.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty, right :-) ?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2019/05/spyder-4-beta2-release/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Labs</category><category>Spyder</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2019/05/spyder-4-beta2-release/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 20:02:50 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>