<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quansight Labs (Posts by Isabela Presedo-Floyd and Juanita Gomez)</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://labs.quansight.org/authors/isabela-presedo-floyd-and-juanita-gomez.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:info@quansight.com"&gt;Quansight Labs Team&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 10:52:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Spot the differences: what is new in Spyder 5?</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/04/spot-the-diffenrences/</link><dc:creator>Isabela Presedo-Floyd and Juanita Gomez</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Spyder 5 versus Spyder 4" src="https://labs.quansight.org/images/spyder5-header.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, Spyder 5 was released at the beginning of April! This 
blog post is a conversation attempting to document the long and complex 
process of improving Spyder's UI with this release. Portions lead by Juanita 
Gomez are marked as &lt;strong&gt;Juanita&lt;/strong&gt;, and those lead by Isabela Presedo-Floyd are 
marked as &lt;strong&gt;Isabela&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What did we do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Juanita]&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.spyder-ide.org/"&gt;Spyder&lt;/a&gt; was created more than 10 
years ago and it has had the contributions of a great number of developers 
who have written code, proposed ideas, opened issues and tested PRs in order 
to build a piece of Spyder on their own. We (the Spyder team) have been lucky 
to have such a great community of people contributing throughout the years, 
but this is the first time that we decided to ask for help from an UX/UI 
expert! Why? You might wonder. Having the contributions of this great amount 
of people has resulted in inconsistencies around Spyder’s interface which we 
didn’t stop to analyze until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Isabela joined Quansight, we realized that we had an opportunity of 
improving Spyder’s interface with her help. We thought her skill set was 
everything we needed to make Spyder’s UI better.  So we started by reviewing 
the results of a community survey from a few months ago and realized that 
some of the most common feedback from users is related to its interface 
(very crowded, not consistent, many colors). This is why we decided to start 
a joint project with Isabela, (who we consider now part of the Spyder team) 
called &lt;a href="https://github.com/spyder-ide/spyder/releases/tag/v5.0.0"&gt;Spyder 5&lt;/a&gt;!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/04/spot-the-diffenrences/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>release</category><category>Spyder</category><category>UX/UI</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/04/spot-the-diffenrences/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>