<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quansight Labs (Posts by Juanita Gomez)</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://labs.quansight.org/authors/juanita-gomez.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:info@quansight.com"&gt;Quansight Labs Team&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 20:48:04 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Spot the differences: what is new in Spyder 5?</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/04/spot-the-diffenrences/</link><dc:creator>Isabela Presedo-Floyd, Juanita Gomez</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Spyder 5 versus Spyder 4" src="https://labs.quansight.org/images/spyder5-header.png"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In case you missed it, Spyder 5 was released at the beginning of April! This 
blog post is a conversation attempting to document the long and complex 
process of improving Spyder's UI with this release. Portions lead by Juanita 
Gomez are marked as &lt;strong&gt;Juanita&lt;/strong&gt;, and those lead by Isabela Presedo-Floyd are 
marked as &lt;strong&gt;Isabela&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;What did we do?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[Juanita]&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.spyder-ide.org/"&gt;Spyder&lt;/a&gt; was created more than 10 
years ago and it has had the contributions of a great number of developers 
who have written code, proposed ideas, opened issues and tested PRs in order 
to build a piece of Spyder on their own. We (the Spyder team) have been lucky 
to have such a great community of people contributing throughout the years, 
but this is the first time that we decided to ask for help from an UX/UI 
expert! Why? You might wonder. Having the contributions of this great amount 
of people has resulted in inconsistencies around Spyder’s interface which we 
didn’t stop to analyze until now. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Isabela joined Quansight, we realized that we had an opportunity of 
improving Spyder’s interface with her help. We thought her skill set was 
everything we needed to make Spyder’s UI better.  So we started by reviewing 
the results of a community survey from a few months ago and realized that 
some of the most common feedback from users is related to its interface 
(very crowded, not consistent, many colors). This is why we decided to start 
a joint project with Isabela, (who we consider now part of the Spyder team) 
called &lt;a href="https://github.com/spyder-ide/spyder/releases/tag/v5.0.0"&gt;Spyder 5&lt;/a&gt;!!!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/04/spot-the-diffenrences/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (8 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>release</category><category>Spyder</category><category>UX/UI</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/04/spot-the-diffenrences/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 16 Apr 2021 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A step towards educating with Spyder</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/04/a-step-towards-educating-with-spyder/</link><dc:creator>Juanita Gomez</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a community manager in the Spyder team, I have been looking for ways of
involving more users in the community and making Spyder useful for a larger
number of people. With this, a new idea came: Education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the past months, we have been wondering with the team whether Spyder
could also serve as a teaching-learning platform, especially in this era
where remote instruction has become necessary. We submitted a proposal to the
Essential Open Source Software for Science (EOSS) program of the Chan
Zuckerberg Initiative, during its third cycle, with the idea of providing a
simple way inside Spyder to create and share interactive tutorials on topics
relevant to scientific research. Unfortunately, we didn’t get this funding,
but we didn’t let this great idea die.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We submitted a second proposal to the &lt;a href="https://www.python.org/psf/"&gt;Python Software Foundation&lt;/a&gt;
from which we were awarded $4000. For me, this is the perfect opportunity for
us to take the first step towards using Spyder for education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/04/a-step-towards-educating-with-spyder/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (2 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>community</category><category>funding</category><category>grant</category><category>Spyder</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/04/a-step-towards-educating-with-spyder/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 14:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Writing docs is not just writing docs</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/07/writing-docs-is-not-just-writing-docs/</link><dc:creator>Juanita Gomez</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I joined the &lt;a href="https://www.spyder-ide.org"&gt;Spyder&lt;/a&gt; team almost two years ago, and I never thought I was going to end up working on docs. Six months ago I started a project with &lt;a href="https://github.com/CAM-Gerlach"&gt;CAM Gerlach&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/ccordoba12"&gt;Carlos Cordoba&lt;/a&gt; to improve Spyder’s documentation. At first, I didn’t actually understand how important docs are for software, especially for open source projects. However, during all this time I’ve learned how documentation has a huge impact on the open-source community and I’ve been thankful to have been able to do this. But, from the beginning, I asked myself “why am I the ‘right person’ for this?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/07/writing-docs-is-not-just-writing-docs/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>documentation</category><category>Labs</category><category>Spyder</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/07/writing-docs-is-not-just-writing-docs/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jul 2020 22:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>