<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../assets/xml/rss.xsl" media="all"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Quansight Labs (Posts by Melissa Weber Mendonça)</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/</link><description></description><atom:link href="https://labs.quansight.org/authors/melissa-weber-mendonca.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link><language>en</language><copyright>Contents © 2021 &lt;a href="mailto:info@quansight.com"&gt;Quansight Labs Team&lt;/a&gt; </copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 10:51:41 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola (getnikola.com)</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>CZI EOSS4 Grants at Quansight Labs</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/08/czi-eoss4-grants-at-quansight-labs/</link><dc:creator>Thomas Fan, Aaron Meurer,Melissa Weber Mendonça,Tania Allard, Matthias Bussonnier, Isabela Presedo-Floyd, Ralf Gommers, Travis Oliphant</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here, at Quansight Labs, our goal is to work on sustaining the future of Open Source. We make sure we can live up to that goal by spending a significant amount of time working on impactful and critical infrastructure and projects within the Scientific Ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As such, our goals align with those of the &lt;a href="https://chanzuckerberg.com"&gt;Chan Zuckerberg Initiative&lt;/a&gt; and, in particular, the &lt;a href="https://chanzuckerberg.com/rfa/essential-open-source-software-for-science/"&gt;Essential Open Source Software for Science&lt;/a&gt; (EOSS) program that supports tools essential to biomedical research via funds for software maintenance, growth, development, and community engagement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CZI’s Essential Open Source Software for Science program supports software maintenance, growth, development, and community engagement for open source tools critical to science. And the Chan Zuckerberg Initiative was founded in 2015 to help solve some of society’s toughest challenges — from eradicating disease and improving education, to addressing the needs of our local communities. Their mission is to build a more inclusive, just, and healthy future for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we are thrilled to announce that the team at Quansight Labs &lt;a href="https://chanzuckerberg.com/newsroom/czi-awards-16-million-for-foundational-open-source-software-tools-essential-to-biomedicine/"&gt;has been awarded&lt;/a&gt; five EOSS Cycle 4 grants to work on several projects within the PyData ecosystem. This post will introduce the successful grantees and their objectives for these two-year long grants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/08/czi-eoss4-grants-at-quansight-labs/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (5 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>CZI</category><category>EOSS</category><category>github-actions</category><category>grants</category><category>Open-Source</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2021/08/czi-eoss4-grants-at-quansight-labs/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 17:01:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A second CZI grant for NumPy and OpenBLAS</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/11/a-second-czi-grant-for-numpy-and-openblas/</link><dc:creator>Melissa Weber Mendonça</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am happy to announce that NumPy and OpenBLAS have once again been awarded a
grant from the Chan Zuckerberg Initiative through
&lt;a href="https://chanzuckerberg.com/newsroom/czi-awards-4-7-million-for-open-source-software-and-organizations-advancing-open-science/"&gt;Cycle 3 of the Essential Open Source Software for Science (EOSS) program&lt;/a&gt;.
This new grant totaling $140,000 will fund part of our efforts to improve
usability and sustainability in both projects and is excellent news for the
scientific computing community, which will certainly benefit from this work
downstream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/11/a-second-czi-grant-for-numpy-and-openblas/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>CZI</category><category>funding</category><category>grant</category><category>NumPy</category><category>OpenBLAS</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/11/a-second-czi-grant-for-numpy-and-openblas/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2020 17:29:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Performance of the Versioned HDF5 Library</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/09/versioned-hdf5-performance/</link><dc:creator>Melissa Weber Mendonça</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In several industry and science applications, a filesystem-like storage model such as &lt;a href="https://www.hdfgroup.org/solutions/hdf5/"&gt;HDF5&lt;/a&gt; is the more appropriate solution for manipulating large amounts of data. However, suppose that data changes over time. In that case, it's not obvious how to track those different versions, since HDF5 is a binary format and is not well suited for traditional version control systems and tools. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/08/introducing-versioned-hdf5/"&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, we introduced the Versioned HDF5 library, which implements a mechanism for storing binary data sets in a versioned way that feels natural to users of other version control systems, and described some of its features. In this post, we'll show some of the performance analysis we did while developing the library, hopefully making the case that reading and writing versioned HDF5 files can be done with a nice, intuitive API while being as efficient as possible. The tests presented here show that using the Versioned HDF5 library results in reduced disk space usage, and further reductions in this area can be achieved with the use of HDF5/&lt;a href="https://www.h5py.org"&gt;h5py&lt;/a&gt;-provided compression algorithms. That only comes at a cost of &amp;lt;10x file writing speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/09/versioned-hdf5-performance/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (14 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>h5py</category><category>HDF5</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/09/versioned-hdf5-performance/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 11:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Introducing Versioned HDF5</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/08/introducing-versioned-hdf5/</link><dc:creator>Melissa Weber Mendonça</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The problem of storing and manipulating large amounts of data is a challenge in
many scientific computing and industry applications. One of the standard data
models for this is &lt;a href="https://support.hdfgroup.org/HDF5/whatishdf5.html"&gt;HDF5&lt;/a&gt;,
an open technology that implements a hierarchical structure (similar to a
file-system structure) for storing large amounts of possibly heterogeneous data
within a single file. Data in an HDF5 file is organized into &lt;em&gt;groups&lt;/em&gt; and
&lt;em&gt;datasets&lt;/em&gt;; you can think about these as the folders and files in your local
file system, respectively. You can also optionally store metadata associated
with each item in a file, which makes this a self-describing and powerful data
storage model.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/08/introducing-versioned-hdf5/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (3 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>h5py</category><category>HDF5</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/08/introducing-versioned-hdf5/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Documentation as a way to build Community</title><link>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/03/documentation-as-a-way-to-build-community/</link><dc:creator>Melissa Weber Mendonça</dc:creator><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a long time user and participant in open source communities, I've always known that documentation is far from being a solved problem. At least, that's the impression we get from many developers: "writing docs is boring"; "it's a chore, nobody likes to do it". I have come to realize I'm one of those rare people who likes to write both code and documentation. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nobody will argue against documentation. It is clear that for an open-source software project, documentation is the public face of the project. The docs influence how people interact with the software and with the community. It sets the tone about inclusiveness, how people communicate and what users and contributors can do. Looking at the results of a “NumPy Tutorial” search on any search engine also gives an idea of the demand for this kind of content - it is possible to find documentation about how to read the NumPy documentation!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I've started working at Quansight in January, and I have started doing work related to the &lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2019/11/numpy-openblas-CZI-grant/"&gt;NumPy CZI Grant&lt;/a&gt;. As a former professor in mathematics, this seemed like an interesting project both because of its potential impact on the NumPy (and larger) community and because of its relevance to me, as I love writing educational material and documentation. Having official high-level documentation written using up-to-date content and techniques will certainly mean more users (and developers/contributors) are involved in the NumPy community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, if everybody agrees on its importance, why is it so hard to write good documentation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/03/documentation-as-a-way-to-build-community/"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt; (4 min remaining to read)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>Labs</category><category>NumPy</category><guid>https://labs.quansight.org/blog/2020/03/documentation-as-a-way-to-build-community/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2020 12:25:55 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>